NYSUT President's Office Files. 6174/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Presidents files: Subseries 2
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    September 15-16, 1989. Agenda; summary of actions; Executive Committee minutes; President's Report; monthly report of NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; financial statements; requests for affiliation; list of PSA (Professional Staff Association) salaries by category, 1988-91; background paper from State Steering Committee in Implementation of Regents Policy on Employment and Secondary Education, with cover memo from State Education Department, August 15; Guidelines for Political Endorsements for NYSUT; "Review of Special Endorsements - Summary, 1980-88," analyzing candidate endorsements by NYSUT (incumbents/challengers/open races, win/loss, NYC/upstate), prepared by NYSUT Legislative Department, June 1989; Report of the Health and Safety Task Force to the Representative Assembly; Testimony of Antonia Cortese, First Vice President, New York State United Teachers, to the Board of Regents on the Regents Legislative Proposals, September 8, 1989; safety and health survey for local presidents; memo re Eastern Airlines and NYNEX strike updates, September 15
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    December 8-9, 1989. Agenda; minutes; Executive Committee minutes; President's Report; financial statements; monthly report of NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services; proposed amendments to 401(k) plans for Professional Staff Association, December 1; revised pension formulas; expense reimbursement policy; proposed revisions from Constitution Revision Committee; NYSUT Constitution as amended through the 1988 Representative Assembly; draft resolutions and other materials for 1990 Representative Assembly; booklet, "Focus on Retirement: The Best of Q and A for '89"; NYSUT press releases and related newspaper clippings re delegation of poll watchers to observe elections in Chile; correspondence re assistance for California earthquake; letter from Communication Workers of America, thanking Hobart for NYSUT's assistance for striking NYNEX workers, December 1; NYSUT Information Bulletin re Consumer Price Index; NYS PTA Annual Convention, November 10-13, 1989, report to NYSUT Board of Directors and staff; directory of sites for NYSUT Educational Research and Dissemination Program, revised November 1989; newsletter of United University Professionals, The Voice, December 1989
  - Lincoln Project, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Press release from Gov. Mario Cuomo's office announcing agreement to publish Polish-language edition of Lincoln on Democracy, July 3, 1990; newspaper clipping from New York Times; resolution unanimously adopted by NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council in support of project to translate Lincoln's writings on democracy into Polish, with cover letter, March 29
  - Local Presidents Letters, 1989-1990 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    Letters re analysis of state aid reduction, December 1990; strike at Daily News, December 7, 1990; questionnaire re NYSUT services, November 21, 1990; NYSUT comments and briefing paper on State Education Department's "New Compact for Learning," October 1990; negotiations with CWA staff (Communication Workers of America), October 1, 1990; update of AFT dues structure for 1990-91; update of 1990 Legislative Report; report on 1990-91 NYS budget enactment; tentative agenda for 1990 Presidents' Conference on Endorsements, June 14, 1990; year-end report re federal legislation; draft analysis by NYSUT of K-12 state aid proposal in Executive Budget, for distribution to state legislators, February 27, 1990; survey on education reform, February 16, 1990; survey on safety and health, September 15, 1989; letter to Long Island local leaders re combatting tax revolt, with attached letter to the editor of the New York Times and response to Newsday editorial, November 21, 1989; letters urging support for VOTE/COPE; 1989 legislative reports; invitation to new local presidents conference; letter re voter registration drive, May 5, 1989; agency fee reduction information, May 2; letter enumerating successful legislative efforts, April 21, 1989; survey of local presidents and delegates re selection of site for Representative Assembly, March 3, 1989; letter to presidents of BOCES affiliates re roundtable with NYSUT president Hobart, February 13; letter to presidents of School-Related Personnel locals re AFT PSRP conference to be held at the same time as Representative Assembly, January 17; memo (January 6, 1989) re key NYSUT program and support bills approved since August 29, 1988; letter re positive feedback for 1988 Educators Income Tax Guide, November 10, 1988; questionnaire for presidents of elementary and secondary teacher locals, October 31, 1988; Preliminary Estimate of 1988-89 Aids Payable under Education Law Section 3609 Plus Other Aids
  - New Local Presidents Conference, 1983-1987 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Evaluation responses; AFL-CIO organizational chart, brochures, newsletters, and other publications; list of labor films for use in elementary and secondary schools, with cover letter re lesson plan and guidelines, "How Schools Are Teaching about Labor," n.d.; Social Education, official journal of the National Center for the Social Studies, re teaching about American labor history, featuring photos of child laborers from 1908 and description of working conditions, February 1982; list of participants in New Presidents Conference, July 9-12, 1984; NYSUT Programs and Services 1983-84; routine correspondence
  - New Local Presidents Conference, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    July 21-24, 1986. Evaluation responses and summary notes; conference agenda for workshop in governance; program; routine correspondence
  - New Local Presidents Conference, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    July 22-25, 1985. Materials on history of NYSUT, including merger and disaffiliation; 1985 participant list; correspondence
  - New Local Presidents Conference, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    July 9-12, 1984. Agenda; booklet by U.S. Department of Labor Bureau of Labor Statistics Brief History of the Labor Movement, 1976 (Bicentennial Edition); excerpt of AFL-CIO publication "A Short History of American Labor," 1981; handwritten notes; letters of invitation, replies, and related correspondence
  - Presidents Conference, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    July 24, 1980. Agenda and tentative program for conference for local presidents on political action; letters of invitation
  - Educational Conference Board (New York State), 1985-1991 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    Resource manual, What's Right with Public Education in New York State, 1985; letter to chair of NYS Educational Conference Board re joint meeting of ECB's State Aid and Ad Hoc Committee, requesting summit of the seven organizational members of ECB, September 27, 1991
  - Educational Conference Board (New York State) Articles of Agreement, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    Articles of Agreement
  - Educational Conference Board (New York State) Editorial Board Meeting, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    Agenda; ECB press release criticizing governor's proposed budget for not doing enough to prevent adult illiteracy, January 31, 1986; reports from the NYS Senate Education Committee, "Project STRIVE: Skills Training Enforcement in Vocational Education," January 1986, and "TIP: Teacher Improvement Program: The Third Year," December 1985; letters to NYSUT president Hobart from committee chair Sen. James Donovan; brochure, 1986-87 State Aid Proposal by the NYS Educational Conference Board; booklet, "ECB Three-Way Comparison: An Analysis of the 1986-87 School Aid Proposals: ECB, Governor, Regents," January 31, 1986; booklet, "46% in '86: 1986-87 Educational Conference Board State Aid Proposal: Background Information," January 13, 1986; 1986-87 Executive Budget Proposal; press release by State Education Department, "Increased Salaries, Improved Working Conditions, Internships Necessary to Strengthen Teaching," January 22, 1986; Legislative Bulletin by NYS School Boards Association, "Upbeat Message Seeks Strengthened Education Initiatives," January 10, 1986; Testimony of Thomas Y. Hobart, Jr., President, New York State United Teachers, at the New York State Senate Education Hearing on Strengthening Teaching in Elementary and Secondary Schools, January 28, 1986; 1986-87 Teacher Salary Aid Executive Budget Recommendations; NYSUT Information Bulletin re 1986-87 Executive Budget Proposal: State Aid to Public Schools, January 1986
  - Chronological Files 1/7/87-4/30/87 (folder 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    Outgoing letters from NYSUT President Tom Hobart
  - Chronological Files 1/7/87-4/30/87 (folder 2 of 2), 1987 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Chronological Files 5/1/87-8/31/87 (folder 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Chronological Files 5/1/87-8/31/87 (folder 2 of 2), 1987 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Chronological Files 9/1/87-1/31/88 (folder 1 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Chronological Files 9/1/87-1/31/88 (folder 2 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Chronological Files 2/1/88-4/29/88 (folder 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Chronological Files 2/1/88-4/29/88 (folder 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Chronological Files 5/4/88-8/29/88 (folder 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Chronological Files 5/4/88-8/29/88 (folder 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Chronological Files 8/31/88-11/15/88 (folder 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Chronological Files 8/31/88-11/15/88 (folder 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Chronological Files 11/16/88-1/30/89 (folder 1 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Files 11/16/88-1/30/89 (folder 2 of 2), 1988-1989 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Files 2/1/89-5/31/89 (folder 1 of 2), 1989 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Files 2/1/89-5/31/89 (folder 2 of 2), 1989 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - NYSUT Task Force on Education Policy (folder 1 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    Binder contents listing task force members, agendas, reports, discussion papers, correspondence
  - NYSUT Task Force on Education Policy (folder 2 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    Memos from State Education Department re testing the language proficiency of prospective teachers, examinations for initial teacher certification; other memos, position papers on Education for a Global Perspective and Education for Values; minutes, and notes
  - Task Force on Education Policy, 1981-1982 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    Agendas; minutes; position papers on early childhood education, computer literacy curriculum guide K-12, and other issues; policy statements on career education and employment preparation, hyperkinesis and food additives, Regents competency tests, curriculum mandate study, teacher evaluation
  - Task Force on Education Policy, 1980-1981 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    Binder contents listing task force members, agendas; minutes; position papers on early childhood education, teaching as a profession, bilingual education, and other subjects
  - Committee on Educational Issues, 1978-1979 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    List of members; correspondence re developing writing skills
  - Committee on Educational Issues (folder 1 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    Binder contents listing committee members, agendas, minutes, draft policy statements
  - Committee on Educational Issues (folder 2 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    Binder contents including correspondence; preliminary report, draft legislation, testimony by Commissioner of Education Gordon Ambach, and other materials on libraries; articles and correspondence on student basic competency tests
  - Educational Issues Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    Binder contents listing committee members, agendas, minutes, draft policy statements and papers, including testing teacher competence; testimony by NYSUT Vice President Antonia Cortese before the Senate Minority Task Force on Education of the Gifted Child, February 20, 1979; testimony to the Board of Regents by Elaine Stoddard, executive chairman, NYS Coordinating Council for the Education of the Gifted/Talented, September 7, 1979; report of NYSUT Teacher Stress Survey, November 1979
  - Educational Issues Committee, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    Draft policy paper on standards and implementation, with comments from individual committee members
  - Educational Issues, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    Report of NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, covering class size, teacher aides, alternative schools, school volunteer programs, instructional innovation and experimentation, instructional television (Project ICEIT), project redesign, career education, alternative salary structures, and teacher evaluations
  - Representative Assembly, 1983 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Program for NYSUT 11th Annual Convention and Education Exhibition
  - Representative Assembly, 1985 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    Program; budget; deadlines; correspondence
  - Representative Assembly Delegate List, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    Delegate list
  - Representative Assembly (folder 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    Program; facilitative correspondence
  - Representative Assembly (folder 2 of 2), 1987 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Representative Assembly Conference Call, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    Printed Convention Call for 16th annual NYSUT Representative Assembly, May 19-22
  - Representative Assembly Elections, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    List of members of Election District (E.D.) Election Committee; list of positions to be filled and election procedures; instructions for district elections committee chairpersons; list of known candidates; mailing label request forms; correspondence
  - Representative Assembly Exhibitions, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    Forms for organizations requesting exhibition space; related correspondence
  - Representative Assembly Finance, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    Invoices and related correspondence re catering, transportation, audiovisual, printing, and other services
  - Representative Assembly Mailings, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    Correspondence re election procedures, journalism competition for retiree editors
  - Representative Assembly Speakers/ Guests, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    List of invited speakers/guests; letters to individual invitees
  - Representative Assembly Staff, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    List of staff; handwritten notes
  - Representative Assembly Masters, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    Originals of correspondence, including specialized letterheads; production schedule for convention Daily Summary; list of delegates
  - Representative Assembly Public Relations, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    Press releases; newsletters; brochure announcing 1987 NYSUT Golden Apple Awards for Excellence in Education Journalism; letter re 1988 journalism competition; convention proceedings daily summaries
  - Representative Assembly, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    Convention Call; report on attendance; evaluation survey results; analysis of feedback re IBM presentation; daily summary of proceedings; newspaper clippings; NYSUT Constitution as amended through the 1987 Representative Assembly; Bottom Line newsletter for local leaders
  - Representative Assembly Amendments / Resolutions, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    NYSUT Constitution, March 1990; constitutional amendments adopted; proposed resolutions; proposed dues recommendation 1991-92 and 1992-93; summary of actions at NYSUT Board of Directors meeting, December 7-8, 1990; list of resolutions and constitutional amendments chairpersons for the past three Representative Assemblies
  - Representative Assembly Committees, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    Letters to sergeants-at-arms and tellers, thanking them for their service; list of responsibilities; lists of sergeants, tellers, and committee chairs; letter re orientation meeting; letters to individuals informing them of their appointments; agendas for NYSUT Representative Assembly Planning Committee/Convention Committee; minutes; Credentials Committee procedures; tentative staffing list
  - Representative Assembly Exhibits, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    Correspondence with vendors, other exhibitors, and members; invoices and related materials with Projection audiovisual services supplier
  - Representative Assembly Housing, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    Correspondence with Sheraton Washington Hotel; marketing materials; catering menu
  - Representative Assembly Kits, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    List of kit contents; NYSUT Constitution; Proposed Resolutions and Constitutional Amendments; Convention Who's Who (list of attendees); report on survey of local assessment of NYSUT services; member benefits progress report; budget summary; Q&A on NYSUT proposed dues increase; book of official prize drawing entry forms; booklet on indoor air pollution; report of the NYSUT Task Force on Student Assessment, "Multiple Choices: Reforming Student Testing in New York State"; 1991 NYSUT legislative program; pad and pen set; badge holder and card with pin
  - Representative Assembly Mailings, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    Convention call; NYSUT Constitution; Implementation of Actions by the 1990 Representative Assembly
  - Representative Assembly Program, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    Printed programs; invitations to special events (receptions, dinners); memos re workshops, VOTE/COPE awards
  - Representative Assembly Speakers and Guests, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    Letters from Tom Hobart to members from various Regional Offices and award recipients, inviting them to attend; agenda of program speakers; list of Members of Congress and other leaders invited to various workshops, indicating whether they would attend; letter from assistant to NY Gov. Mario Cuomo, declining to commit the governor to attending as keynote speaker, November 29, 1990; related correspondence
  - Representative Assembly Transportation, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    List of travelers; related correspondence
  - Representative Assembly, 1990 (Box 69, Folder 25)
    Report on attendance; daily summaries of the proceedings; review of evaluations, with summary response sheet
  - Representative Assembly Amendments and Resolutions (folder 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 69, Folder 26)
    Proposed resolutions and amendments; Report of Resolutions Committee; assignment of resolutions and special orders of business for implementation; additional recommendations for constitutional revisions; effect of revision on members' dues; minutes of the Constitutional Revision Committee, August 26, 1989, and September 16, 1986; selected statistics; proposed resolutions submitted by local teacher associations; letters to local presidents rejecting resolutions for submission after the deadline
  - Representative Assembly Amendments and Resolutions (folder 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    Hotel guest list and event resume; binder contents with tabbed sections for program, floor plans, housing, supplies, exhibits, committees/procedures; minutes of Credential Committee meeting
  - Representative Assembly Committees, 1990 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    Folders for district elections, resolutions, RA elections, sergeants-at-arms, and tellers
  - Representative Assembly Credentials, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    List of Credentials Committee members; list of retiree delegates and alternates; correspondence
  - Representative Assembly Elections, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Correspondence; instructions for district elections committee chairpersons; ballots and envelopes; candidacy announcement forms; list of positions to be filled; election supplement to New York Teacher
  - Representative Assembly Exhibits, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    Marketing materials for United Exposition Service Company; marketing materials for the Freeman Companies
  - Representative Assembly Finance, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Invoices from suppliers; envelope of ribbons designating status of attendees
  - Representative Assembly Housing (folder 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    Contract with New York Hilton
  - Representative Assembly Housing (folder 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    Master account folder; marketing brochure for new Hilton convention space; room list
  - Representative Assembly Kits (folder 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    List of items for Delegate Kit; NYSUT Constitution; Convention Call; Convention Who's Who (list of attendees); 1990 Annual Report; Budget Summary 1989-90: Distribution of the NYSUT Dues Dollar; Major Legislation of Interest to Higher Education and Health Care Professionals 1989; Focus on K-12 1989; The Easter Shuffle: Songs for the Eastern [Airlines] Picket Line; NYSUT pin and cord
  - Representative Assembly Kits (folder 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    Proposed Resolutions and Constitutional Amendments; NYSUT 1990 Legislative Program; Questions and Answers on Proposed Constitutional Amendment #4; Focus on Retirement: The Best of "On Retirement" for 89: New York City Teachers' Retirement System; Focus on Retirement: The Best of Q and A for '89: New York State Teachers' Retirement System; brochure re NYSUT Member Benefits; map of regional offices and photos of regional directors; brochure, NYSUT statement on Academic Freedom
  - Representative Assembly Mailing, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    Proposed rules of order, nominating petitions, and other instructions and forms sent to Election District directors and delegates; list of sergeants-at-arms and tellers
  - Representative Assembly Masters, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    Originals of forms and other materials, with printing orders/invoices
  - Representative Assembly Printing, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    Daily summaries of proceedings; Report of the Resolutions Committees; press releases; forms and other materials with attached printing orders
  - Representative Assembly Public Relations / New York Teacher, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    List of articles in New York Teacher, publicizing Representative Assembly; sample issue
  - Representative Assembly Program, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    Printed programs; schedule of events and speakers; petition for display space for gay teachers and AIDS Walk information; printing order with color and type specifications
  - Representative Assembly Speakers and Guests, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    Letters from Tom Hobart to state, union, and other leaders, inviting them to attend; list of confirmed guests as of March 5, 1990
  - Representative Assembly Staff, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    Tentative staffing list; agendas and minutes for R.A. Planning Committee; list of equipment needs; transportation list; memo re print deadlines
  - Representative Assembly Storage, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    Additional copies of 1990 Annual Report, daily summaries of proceedings
  - Contracting Out Alert, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    Newsletter of the AFT
  - Post-QuEST Manual c., 1980 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    American Federation of Teachers guide for AFT leaders, n.d., c. 1980
  - AFT Teacher Centers: Putting the Pieces Together for Success, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    Binder contents with cover letter to AFT Executive Council, February 5, 1979; publications in the "How To" series: Be an Effective Consultant, Be a Teacher Author, Develop Cultural Awareness; cassette tapes of Al Shanker speech and interview with Pat Weiler at USOE Teacher Center Program, Sept. 26, 1978, and Charles Lovett, August 27, 1978
  - AFL-CIO Public Employee Department Resource Manual, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 4)